Adult Student Personnel Association (ASPA) Records
Adult Student Personnel Association (ASPA) Records
1961-1980
Adult Student Personnel Association
2 linear ft.
Records include conference proceedings and programs, correspondence, directories, lists, newsletters, and other publications. Records from both the Adult Student Personnel Association and the Evening Student Personnel Association are included as well as material from organizations with whom ASPA had close ties, such as the Coalition of Adult Education Organizations and the United States Association of Evening Students. Correspondents whose letters are of greatest depth and duration include Robert A. Allen and Edward Phoenix.
149432
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Adult Student Personnel Association (ASPA) was originally founded as the Evening Student Personnel Association (ESPA). The name was officially changed to the ASPA in March, 1968. The activities of the ESPA are reflected in its newsletter, journal ( Journal of Student Personnel Work in Adult and Evening Education), and annual conventions. The newsletters and journal were published irregularly, but after 1963, a convention was held every year except 1972. In 1973, ASPA held its tenth annual convention and republished a collection of articles from its journal under the title A Decade of Development. Throughout most of its existence, ASPA maintained strong ties with the United States Associate of Evening Students (USAES) and the Coalition of Adult Education Organizations (CAEO).
Papers from the ASPA were collected by several individuals, but largely represent the contributions of Edward Phoenix and Robert A. Allen, both of whom were longstanding members, presidents, and executive board members. Consequently some files may overlap or duplicate one another; in other places, large gaps occur. The files in the ASPA collection are arranged by type and chronologically wherever possible. Files are labeled ESPA or ASPA to correspond with the name of the organization when the papers were produced. Some papers have no date.
Related Material
The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Allen, Robert A.; Phoenix, Edward; Coalition of Adult Education Organizations; Evening Student Personnel Association; United States Association of Evening Students; Adult education; Continuing education; Correspondence.; Lists.; Newsletters.; Proceedings.; Programs (documents); Teachers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Robert Allen, 1986.
Inventory
- Executive Board
  - Minutes
    - ESPA, 1962-1968 (Box 1)
    - ASPA, 1968-1971 (Box 1)
    - ASPA, 1972-1976 (Box 1)
  - Officers, 1963-1967 (Box 1)
  - Elections, 1974-1976 (Box 1)
  - Archives, 1973 (Box 1)
- Publications
  - Newsletters
    - ESPA, 1961-1966 (Box 1)
    - ESPA - Editor's notes, 1961-1967 (Box 1)
    - ASPA, 1968-1975 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 1)
  - Journals, 1968-1974 (Box 1)
  - Publications - correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
  - Special mailings, 1966-1973 (Box 1)
  - Brochures, 1970-1974 (Box 1)
  - Decade of Development, 1973 (Box 1)
- Annual conference
  - 1st-8th, programs, 1963-1970 (Box 1)
  - 1st-4th, proceedings, 1963-1966 (Box 1)
  - 3rd-4th, announcements. notes, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - 6th-7th, proceedings, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - 8th, Atlantic City, NJ, 1970 (Box 1)
  - 9th, New Hope, PA, 1971 (Box 1)
  - 10th, Washington, DC, 1972-1974 (Box 1)
  - 11th, Ft. Mitchell, KY, 1975 (Box 1)
  - 12th, New York, NY, 1975 (Box 1)
  - 13th, Chicago, IL, 1976; Correspondence, D. Becker / R.A. Allen (Box 1)
  - 14th, plans, 1977 (Box 1)
- Constitution
  - ESPA, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - ASPA, 1968-1973; Constitution and incorporation (Box 1)
- Finances
  - Miscellaneous reports, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous bills, correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Finanes and tax exempt status, 1971-1978 (Box 1)
- Organization status
  - Miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 1)
- Membership
  - Membership cards, 1963-1966 (Box 2)
  - Directories, 1963-1974 (Box 2)
  - Directory correspondence, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Lists and mailing labels, 1966-1969 (Box 2)
  - Lists, 1968-1974 (Box 2)
  - Campaign, 1971 (Box 2)
- Correspondence
  - General, 1972-1976 (Box 2)
  - Phoenix, Ed, 1972-1975 (Box 2)
  - Allen, Robert A., 1974-1978 (Box 2)
- Adult education organizations and publications
  - Counseling and Personnel Services in Adult Education - ERIC, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Kellogg Directory, Community and Junior Colleges, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Coalition of Adult Education Organizations
    - Ray Ast, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Transactions, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Adult Education Clearinghouse, newsletter, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Association of University Evening Colleges
    - Newsletter, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Directories, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - United States Association of Evening Students
    - Miscellaneous, 1974 (Box 2)
    - USAEA/ASPA joint meeting, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Adult education organizations, various, 1974-1980 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous conferences and workshops
  - International Association of Evening Student Councils, annual conference (New York City), 1965 (Box 2)
  - Future Shock Workshop, 1973 (Box 2)
  - American College Personnel Association, Commission XIII, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Serving the Elderly Workshop, 1974 (Box 2)
- Monographs
  - Miscellaneous, 1974; undated (Box 2)